What we're going to do now is, for your exercise,
you'll notice that inside we have this ability to filter, right?
As the user types.
But the thing is, this can be a little bit tricky,
because sometimes the user's not ready for you to filter
and you just immediately eliminating it.
So what I want you to do is, inside of this,
whether, let's just do dishes to be consistent,
I want you to hijack the events
so that it only like grad, like updates
and grads the latest once you've hit enter.
We'll walk through the solution, and then I might show you
easier way to do it.
So let's recap, so what we're trying to do here
is inside of our dishes.
Currently, whenever we type it automatically filters,
which is nice on one hand.
But on the other hand, let's actually make it so that
users are intention about when they want to filter
in case they're trying to look at something
and reference it as they're typing to kind of make a guess.
So the way we're going to do this is start by
actually breaking apart the V model that exists
on the input element.
So this filter text V model that's happening,
we can basically say then is that we can break it up
into the value that we want to be defined.
But then we have this input where we say,
basically let's call it update filter text.
All right, so this method for update filter text,
let's define that up here.
So it can't update filter text.
Now we know a couple of things.
We know one, we're getting an event,
but what kind of event are we getting?
We're getting an input event.
And then, what we do want to then
is we want to check to see basically,
can we actually see something specific about it?
And so let's go ahead and start just by making sure
that the event actually triggers and fires.
So we go back here and look at our console.
We can see when we type, okay, this is good.
FDS perfect.
But I'm kind of curious though,
what if I swapped this to be a keyboard event?
Instead, if I swap that over,
it looks like it still causes it calling it as an input event,
but I see if this doesn't anything for us.
Because on the keyboard event,
the nice thing is we get some other things
that we know we get as far as like the code
on the actual key event that's being pressed.
So the key event, then we can also just say like this,
and then that way when we go back, let's try this out.
So there we go, it's undefined.
Oh, that's interesting.
And so it looks like it's because at the moment,
this input event really doesn't have it.
So we can't, you see, we can't like, we can't fake it.
Even though TypeScript is being like, you're good.
No, you're not really good.
Clearly something is wrong.
So we can't, we can't just arbitrarily change it.
So we have our input event, and that's fine.
And so once again, we can go ahead and say, alright,
so we have event.target as HTML input element.
And then let's log that once again real quick,
and then once we refresh, there we go.
We have some stuff here going on,
and then we can basically then grab the,
well, actually, we don't want the value.
Well, we do want, well, we want this in a second.
So we do want, we want to get the key somehow from this.
It's kind of interesting that the key doesn't pop up.
But, okay, there we go.
It's trusted.
Let's see, where is that data?
I mean, if we hit Enter, what does that, what does that create for us?
Nothing.
It's interesting.
Enter doesn't do anything for us.
So, what do we want to do, do, do, do, do, do?
So maybe actually, the more,
so I'm sure there's a way you can dive in,
you can look into things.
But, this is where actually the input event might not actually be the right thing to be listening for on this.
In fact, and so this is a little bit of a gadget.
It's kind of done intentionally.
What we might want to do instead is actually do the key up event.
And so if you haven't worked with the view native events before,
it allows you to basically attach to any native JavaScript event,
and work with it.
And so, on the key up event, now let's see what exactly do we get from this.
So, see, key up has a keyboard event.
Oh, okay, this looks a little bit more interesting.
So, let's swap that over now to a keyboard event.
So that's really what we're looking for.
And let's go ahead and see how, if this changes anything.
So, now we can go ahead and let's go in here and be like,
okay, wait, oh, I'm going to add issues.
This is correct.
Oh, look, the code, the magic code has appeared.
So, if I hit enter, hey, it's appearing.
So, what we can do is we can say, well,
if event.code is equal to enter,
then we shall do our thing where we do dish.
Wait, new dish.
I believe, new dish.
Oh, wait, am I in?
Oh, wait, I forgot.
We're filtering text.
We're not updating the new text.
So, we need to update its filter text.
So, filter text.value is equal to,
let's see, event.target.
We'll let that last do it.
It does not.
Okay, so now we know, once again,
this is nature and input element.
So, we need to cast it.
So, let's go and cast it as an element.
Then, this gives us the value.
So, now, we can try this out.
It goes, hey, nothing's changing yet.
But if I hit enter, everything filters.
But, that's not it.
That's actually not the easiest way to do this.
The easiest way to do this is we can actually delete all this.
And then, we can actually attach a modifier to our events.
So, this allows you to basically already bypass the key check.
So, if I save this now and then go back here,
you can see a little more enter refreshes or well filters.
And so, chaining events is a popular thing in view.
And so, something I want you all to know about.
Because, for example, when you're doing a form,
how many of us have done forms where when we have to listen to a submit event,
run event.prevent default, well,
whenever you're building a view, just do this.
Submit.prevent, your code is much cleaner.
You don't have to worry about preventing the default event.
So, definitely looking to the event chaining going forward.
There's a lot in there, a lot more than when I've shown you.
In fact, you can even write your own custom modifiers.
This whole thing you can customize.
But, I just wanted you to see the kind of syntactic sugar
that you can provide for you.
That can make things just a lot easier.
But, again, just to be clear, I wanted you all to get what
was like to get at the raw primitives of it.
In case you needed to get at that level.
So, there we go.
That's how we would complete.